现在我们将考虑相机正在观察一堆点和这些点的情况
Now we will consider the case where a camera is looking at a bunch of points and these
所有点都在飞机上。飞机有自己的坐标系，我们用它来表示
points all lie on a plane. The plane has got its own coordinate system which we denote
通过坐标框架零。显然，这个平面上的每个点都有一个Z坐标
by coordinate frame zero. Clearly every point that lies on this plane has got a Z coordinate
零，这在这里显示。坐标大写Z乘以所有元素
of zero, which is shown down here. The coordinate capital Z multiples all of the elements in
我们的相机矩阵的第三列，但因为它是零，我们可以有效地删除
the third column of our camera matrix but because it's zero we can effectively remove
矩阵中的那一列，我们可以从世界坐标向量中删除该行。
that column from the matrix and we can remove that row from the world coordinate vector.
我们现在剩下的是一个三乘三矩阵，我们将这三个三个参考
What we're left with now is a three by three matrix and we'll refer to this three by three
矩阵作为“平面同构”。
matrix as a "Planar Homography".
就像相机矩阵一样，有一个任意比例因子，我们可以再次
Just as for the camera matrix, there is an arbitrary scale factor and once again we can
通过选择我们要去的一个特定元素来标准化单应矩阵
normalize the homography matrix by choosing one particular element that we're going to
设置为值1。所以这三个三个矩阵，我们有一个元素
set to the value of one. So this three by three matrix, it's got one element that we've
设置为1，单应矩阵中剩余8个唯一数字。和我们
set to one, there are eight unique numbers remaining in the homography matrix. And we
如果我们有四个世界点和相应的位置，则可以估计单应矩阵
can estimate the homography matrix if we have four world points and the corresponding position
这些点在我们相机的图像平面上。
of those points on the image plane of our camera.
所以对应点的概念，想象我有两架飞机，其中一架也许是
So the concept of corresponding points, imagine that I've got two planes, one is perhaps the
相机的图像平面，另一个可能是世界上的物理平面那个
image plane of the camera, the other might be a physical plane in the world that the
相机正在看着。或者，第一个可以是世界上飞机的视图
camera is looking at. Alternatively the first could be a view of a plane in the world and
第二幅图像可能是世界上同一平面的另一个视图，我们已经移动了
the second image could be another view of the same plane in the world, where we've moved
两个视图之间的摄像头。
the camera between the two views.
现在我们在每个飞机上都有四个点，我将用下标来表示
Now we've got four points in each of these planes, which I'm going to denote by the subscripts
一到四，我打算将这些点的坐标安排到
one through four and I'm going to arrange the coordinates of those points into the
矩阵的列。但是这里真正重要的是这些列的排序。我们
columns of a matrix. But what's really important here is the ordering of these columns. We
必须确保所谓的通信。P1和Q1必须对应于同一点
have to ensure what's called correspondence. P1 and Q1 must correspond to the same point
在世界上，它适用于P2，P3和P4。每个点P和对应点
in the world and so it goes for P2, P3 and P4. Each point P and the corresponding point
Q必须指向世界上的同一点。
Q must refer to the same point in the world.
让我们看看如何使用这种技术来执行某些操作的实际示例
Let's look at a practical example of how we can use this technique to perform something
称为“透视矫正”。现在这是我拍摄的巴黎圣母院的照片
called "Perspective Rectification". Now this is a picture that I took of the Notre Dame
在巴黎的大教堂。
Cathedral in Paris.
这是一个非常高的大教堂，所以我在前面的地面上，仰视并拍照。
It's a very tall cathedral, so I'm on the ground in front, looking up and taking a picture.
很明显，因为我的相机向上倾斜，我的前方视野非常扭曲
And clearly because my camera is tilted upwards I've got a very distorted view of the front
大教堂但我知道有关大教堂的一些事情，特别是我知道
of the cathedral. But I know some things about cathedrals and particularly I know that the
大教堂前面最有可能是一架飞机。
front of the cathedral is most likely to be a plane.
因此，如果我在大教堂前面选择四个点，我相信所有这些都在一个单一的位置
So if I pick four points on the front of the cathedral that I believe all lie in a single
我可以将它们标记为P1到P4。但我知道那些点在非扭曲
plane and I can label them P1 through to P4. But I know that those points in a non-distorted
图像将在图像平面中形成一个矩形，而不是一个梯形。我可以计算图像平面
image will form a rectangle in the image plane, not a trapezoid. I can compute the image plane
坐标Q1，Q2，Q3和Q4，以便在图像中有一个矩形。所以，如果我有
coordinates Q1, Q2, Q3 and Q4 in order to have a rectangle in the image. So if I have
现在有两套对应点;我有积分P1到P4，我有积分
now two sets of corresponding points; I have the points P1 through P4 and I have the points
从Q1到Q4，我可以计算出单应性。
Q1 through Q4, then I can compute a homography.
因此，如果我建立一个矩阵P，其中包含点P1到P4和列的列
So if I build up a matrix P that contains as columns the points P1 through P4 and the
矩阵Q，其列是Q1到Q4的点，然后我可以计算单应性。
matrix Q, whose columns are the points Q1 through Q4, then I can compute a homography.
它在这里显示，在MATLAB中非常简单。现在我有了这个单应性
And it's shown here and very simple to do in MATLAB. Now that I have this homography
矩阵H，我可以用它来将我原始图像中的任何点P转换为任意点，Qin
matrix H, I can use it to transform any point, P, in my original image, to any point, Q in
第二张图片。
a second image.
这就是第二张图片的样子。我们看到大教堂已被拉直了
And this is what the second image looks like. We see that the cathedral has been straightened
起来。我们可以看到大教堂的垂直边缘实际上是垂直线
up. We can see that the vertical edges of the cathedral are in fact vertical lines in
图片。重要的是要记住，在这方面做出了非常强烈的假设
the image. It's important to remember that there's a very strong assumption made in this
这个过程就是图像中的所有点都在一个平面上。
process and that is that all of the points in the image lie on a plane.
当然，这张照片中的许多点都位于大教堂的正面，
Certainly many of the points in this image lay on the frontal plane of the cathedral,
但不是全部都这样做。如果我们看看这里的点，这些点位于钟楼的边缘，
but not all do. If we look at points around here, which are on the edges of the bell towers,
那么他们就不会躺在正面上而且转型也不正确
then they do not lay on the frontal plane and the transformation won't be correct for
他们。它会在图像的那一部分引入失真。你无法得到任何东西
them. It will introduce a distortion in that part of the image. You can't get anything
免费，我们当然证明了大教堂的几何正确性。
for free, we've certainly proved that geometric correctness of the bulk of the cathedral.
鉴于我使用MATLAB计算了矩阵H，那么这是一个非常简单的问题
Given that I've computed the matrix H using MATLAB, then it's a very simple matter to
将单应性应用于图像中的每个点。我们通过一个过程来执行
apply the homography to every single point in the image. And we perform that by a process
被称为“形象翘曲”。
known as "Image Warping".
要做图像变形，我们可以看到输出图像和输出中的每个像素
To do image warping, we can see that every single pixel in the output image and the output
在这种情况下，图像是几何校正的，大教堂的矫正图像。
image in this case is the geometrically correct, the rectified image of the cathedral.
为了说明这一点，我将在输出图像中选择一个特定点
To illustrate this I’m going to choose just one particular point in the output image and
它是坐标600,100处的像素。现在，如果我知道像素坐标，我想
it’s the pixel at coordinate 600,100. Now if I know that pixel coordinate, I want to
尝试找出输入图像中相应的像素坐标。
try and work out what's the corresponding pixel coordinate in the input image.
单应性是从原始图像到新图像的映射，因此为了映射
The homography is a mapping from the original image to the new image, so in order to map
这个坐标我需要使用单应性的逆，这给了我坐标
this coordinate I need to use the inverse of the homography and that gives me the coordinate
在输入图像中的对应点，它的坐标为757和51。
of the corresponding point in the input image and it's got a coordinate of 757 and 51.
然后，图像变形的工作方式是在坐标757,51处找到像素
The way image warping works then is we go and find the pixel at coordinate 757, 51
我们取这个像素值，然后将它插入到坐标600处的新图像中，
and we take that pixel value and we insert it into the new image at coordinate 600,
因此，对于输出图像中的每个像素，我们计算出来自哪里
100. So for every single pixel in the output image, we work out where it comes from in
输入图像。
the input image.
您可以在此处看到输入图像中的坐标是小数且需要的
You can see here that the coordinates in the input image are fractional and that requires
一种称为图像插值的技术，用于查找此处的实际像素值
a technique called image interpolation to find what is the actual pixel value at this
特定的分数坐标。简而言之，这是图像变形的过程。
particular fractional coordinate. In a nutshell, that's the process of image warping.
图像变形的另一个应用是现在在游泳电视广播中经常使用的效果，
Another application of image warping is this often used effect now in swimming telecasts,
我们拿旗帜和竞争对手的名字，我们将它们叠加在车道上
where we take the flag and the name of the competitors and we overlay them on the lanes
游泳池。这实际上是一个很容易的技巧，它涉及到这些
of the swimming pool. It's actually quite an easy trick to do and it involves these
单应性。
homographies.
现在形象我可以游得很好，足以进入游泳比赛，所以有
Now image that I could swim well, well enough to get into a swimming tournament, so there's
我的国旗，这是我的名字。现在我有了这个我创建的图像，只是使用普通的
my flag and there's my name. Now I've got this image that I created, just using ordinary
计算机图形学，这很容易。现在我想把那张照片放在我的车道上
computer graphics, that's the easy bit. Now I want to lay that image into my lane in the
游泳池。我需要做的就是找到四个相应的点，所以
swimming pool. All I need to do that, is to find the four corresponding points, so the
这个矩形的四个角，用于保存我想要叠加的图像和四个
four corners of this rectangle that holds the image that I want to overlay and the four
在游泳池里，我希望它被放置。
points in the swimming pool where I'd like it to be laid.
一旦我掌握了这些信息，我就可以将原始图像扭曲成这个非常扭曲的图像
Once I have that information I can warp that original image into this very distorted image
然后我可以插入或叠加到游泳池的原始图像上。
which I could then insert into or overlay onto the original image of the swimming pool.
那些正在做与该课程相关的项目的人，单应性正在进行中
Those of you who are doing the project associated with this course, the homography is going
非常非常有用。你可能已经建立了一个二维机器人，坐在上面
to be very, very useful. You've probably already built a two dimensional robot, that sits on
工作表，可以将其末端效应器移动到机器人上的任何特定XY坐标
a worksheet and can move its end effector to any particular XY coordinate on the robot
工作表。
worksheet.
现在我们拍摄机器人工作表的照片。我有机器人工作表的图像。
Now image that we take a picture of that robot worksheet. I have an image of the robot worksheet.
单应性让我在工作表的图像中创建一个坐标，
The homography lets me create a mapping between a coordinate in the image of the worksheet,
在图像平面上有一个U，V的坐标，我可以将它映射到一个物理
which has got a coordinate of U,V in the image plane and I can map that to a physical
机器人工作表上的坐标X，Y。我可以从图像平面坐标映射
coordinate, X,Y on the robot's worksheet. I can map from an image plane coordinate
到机器人工作表坐标，或者我可以从机器人工作表坐标向后映射
to a robot worksheet coordinate, or I can map from a robot worksheet coordinate back
到相机图像坐标。
to a camera image coordinate.
现在单应性对你完成项目非常非常有帮助。
Now homography's are going to be very, very helpful for you in completing the project.
只是总结工具箱中用于计算和使用单应性的功能。特定
Just to summaries the capability in the toolbox for computing and using homographies. Given
两组对应点P和Q，我们可以计算出三乘三的单应性
two sets of corresponding points P and Q, we can compute a three by three homography
矩阵。P和Q的列代表点。现在P可能是已知的图像坐标
matrix. The columns of P and Q represent points. Now P might be image coordinates of known
在图像中的点，Q可能是机器人物理工作表上的点的坐标。
points in an image, Q might be coordinates of points on the robot's physical worksheet.
或者，P可以是一个图像中的一组图像坐标，Q可以是一组图像
Alternatively P could be a set of image coordinates in one image and Q could be a set of image
坐标在另一个图像。鉴于我有三乘三的单应矩阵
coordinates in another image. Given that I have the three by three homography matrix
然后，我可以在第一平面中将一组点P映射到第二平面中的一组点Q.
H, I can then map a set of points P, in the first plane, to a set of points Q, in the second plane.